on the subject of um of tatan and
Angiotensin receptor blockers in general
um I you it's become very popular tatan
um just purely because this this was off
the back of um some studies done a long
time ago back in 2009 there was a big
study called On Target um and then there
was the transcend study as well which
specifically looked at um what they
would call maintenance dosing of Telma
Satan um in terms of cardio protection
um and uh and they they specifically
looked at at this ARB rather than uh ACE
inhibitors because of its tolerance and
safety profile um so because with with
ACE inhibitors you you can run into all
kinds of issues um if you take other
medications especially if you're a
diabetic um or you have um other sort of
cardio cardiovascular drugs if you have
other cardiac issues um but it's it's
exceptionally good at um keeping your
blood pressure under control if you are
hypertensive in a dose dependent manner
throughout 24-hour period that's why
they like tatan for for um sort of first
line ARB use um but yeah the the
untargeted transcend studies did look
specifically at Cardio protection so in
terms of longevity and found it to um be
particularly useful um for reducing um
sorry preventing new onset of diabetes
type two diabetes was one of the
outcomes and also uh it reduced people
uh that had fast AF or atrial fi
fibrillation um and that was as a direct
result of controlling their their
slightly hypertensive State um so the
the conferred benefit for it in terms of
taking it as a maintenance do for
someone who doesn't have those uh
pre-existing conditions um is uh is
based on those studies so it's it stands
to reason that it would provide good
cardiovascular protection and that was
found in both of those studies back in
the early 2000s
[Music]